Alejandro Rodriguez

Los Angeles, CA | av.rodriguez@outlook.com | (805) 663-3519

SUMMARY

Analytical and solution-based professional with +6 years of experience in sales, project management and customer service in the technology field. Track record of successful software sales, optimizing company practices and understanding client issues to achieve better solutions. Eager to leverage extensive problem-solving experience along with acquired software knowledge to build useful software solutions that impact the world.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, Java, Python, HTML5, CSS, Mern | **Frameworks/Libraries**: Flask, React, Express, Jinja2, J Query, Bootstrap, Tailwind | **Databases**: MySQL, MongoDB | **Tools**: VSC, STS, Postman, MySQL Workbench, Github, Git, AJAX, json, AWS, SpringToolSuite, Rest API's.

TECHNICAL PROJECTS

Musicon | Python, MySQL, AJAX, HTML, CSS | Full-Stack Project

- Developed a login/registration system using RegEx validation and Bcrypt.
- Employed a Flask framework for quick implementation of features with Jinja2 like flash messages.
- Designed a front-end with clean and engaging user experience.

Library | Java, SpringToolSuite, MySQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap

- Developed a login/registration system with validation and session.
- Employed a full CRUD application with session for a more unique experience for the user.
- Designed a front-end with clean and engaging user experience.

RandomRe | JavaScript, React, CSS, Express, RecipesAPI

- Developed a recipe generator with responsive web design.
- Employed API calls to generate random recipes for the user.
- Designed a front-end with clean and engaging user experience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

SDR | ShipERP | Long Beach, CA

2019-2022

- Expanded international clientele through breaking language barriers of communication, optimizing client's supply chain with our solution written in ABAP using SAP's Api.
- Lead communication with clients and prospects, understanding the current issues and needs to report these findings to the team, improving product efficiency and corrections.
- Represented the company at National SAP and Software Conferences and Events.

SDR | Hacienda Furniture | Oxnard, CA.

2018-2019

- Boosted sales and delivery times by suggesting renting a new warehouse in a strategic location that allowed us to have more
 inventory and mobility of our furniture.
- Upgraded data capture since the company was still using paper. Utilized a new software for the company and started capturing data in a more efficient way.

Project Manager | *Vinik* | Mexico City, MX

2015-2018

- Pioneered and founded the company, recruited and trained 8 successful financial agents. As a team, we got our place in one of the most important newspapers in Mexico City as one of the youngest successful fintech companies.
- Partnered with ComparaGuru, one of the biggest online travel agencies in Latin America to offer financial services to people.
 Our company was able to maximize revenue.

EDUCATION

Coding Dojo | Full-Stack Developer Certificate | Los Angeles, CA.

2022

• Immersive Full-Stack Training Program in Web Fundamentals (JS, HTML, CSS), Python, Java, and MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node)

Escuela Bancaria y Comercial | Bachelors in International Business and Commerce | Mexico City

• Bachelor's Degree: Successfully completed my degree with honors in the EGEL exam.